

Varvara Lazarenko

Address Nijmegen, The Netherlands

Telephone +31 6 2662 9839

E-mail varlazoa@gmail.com

Date of birth 29.12.1998 (26 years) **LinkedIn** www.linkedin.com/in/varvara-lazo

PERSONAL STATEMENT

I am a curious and dedicated graduate with a Master's degree in Medical Biology, driven by a passion for advancing healthcare through science. My experience spans both fundamental research and clinical trial development. With a solid biomedical background and a keen interest in sharing knowledge, I am motivated to grow within clinical research field, health technology assessment, or academia.

EDUCATION

09/2022 - 08/2024 MSc in Medical Biology - Radboud University, Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ <u>Specialisation</u>: Science, Management and Innovation
- ✓ GPA result: 7.63/10.00
- ✓ <u>Principal subjects</u>: Future of health, How Health Systems Work, Sustainable Innovation Management, Methods in Societal Research, Molecular Therapy, Trends in Stem Cell Biology
- ✓ <u>Master thesis</u>: «Potential added value of home telemonitoring technology in elderly care», GPA result: 8.00/10.00

09/2016 - 06/2020 BSc in Biology - Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU), Moscow, Russia

- ✓ <u>Specialisation</u>: Human and Animal Physiology
- ✓ GPA result: 4.83/5.00
- ✓ <u>Principal subjects</u>: Human and animal physiology, Electrophysiology of excited cells, Physiology of central nervous and visceral systems, Physiology of circulation, Embryology, Genetics, Microbiology, Biochemistry, Immunology
- ✓ <u>Skills</u>: PCR, qPCR, RT-PCR, gel electrophoresis, wire myography, western blotting, ELISA, microscopy, cell culture, immunohistochemistry, intracellular recording (microelectrodes, patch clamp), behaviour tests (open field test, elevated plus maze, light-dark box test)
- ✓ <u>Bachelor thesis</u>: «Role of TASK-1 channels in arterial tone regulation in different organs in rats», GPA result: 5.00/5.00

WORK EXPERIENCE

10/2024 - current Part-time staff while searching for a life sciences position Renato's Pizzeria - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ Providing customer service
- ✓ Selling the restaurant's menu

02/2024 - 08/2024 Intern at <u>Digital Transformation of Rehabilitation Care</u>

HAN University of Applied Sciences - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ Added value research of home telemonitoring in elderly care based on the HTA framework presented onto the Quadruple aim
- ✓ Deployment of surveys (22) in Dutch and interviewing (7) medical professionals in English on their home telemonitoring experience/attitude
- ✓ Cost-effectiveness analysis (Markov model cohort simulation) on home telemonitoring in the Netherlands

02/2023 - 08/2023 Intern at Neuronal Networks of Memory

Donders Institute - Nijmegen, The Netherlands

- ✓ In vivo Ca²+ imaging of the retrosplenial cortex in mice during head-fixed virtual social learning using two-photon microscopy
- ✓ Management of laboratory animals (GCaMP6 transgenic mice, handling & feeding, craniotomy)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (Python, DeepLabCut)

08/2021 - 08/2022 Assistant at the Science Department of the Contract Research Organization

LABMGMU, LLC - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Developing designs, synopses, protocols, investigator's brochures for >35 phase I, II, III clinical trials and bioequivalence trials
- √ >30 user interviews (testing the readability of pharmaceuticals' package leaflets)
- ✓ Advising on the number & design of (pre-)clinical studies for pharma clients
- ✓ Project management (control of the deadlines; compliance with the sponsor's requirements)
- ✓ Computational analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)

10/2020 - 10/2021 Junior Research Assistant at Faculty of Biology

Lomonosov Moscow State University - Moscow, Russia

- ✓ Physiological (wire myography technique, rat coronary and renal arteries) and molecular (RNA extraction, reverse transcription, qPCR) experiments
- ✓ Management of laboratory animals (Wistar rats: housing, care, breeding)
- ✓ Statistical analysis of the obtained data (STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism)
- ✓ Project management (experiment and research strategy planning)
- ✓ Presentation of the results at the <u>virtual conference ARTERY20</u>, 23-24 October 2020, and at the <u>28th International Scientific Conference "Lomonosov-2021"</u>, 12-23 April 2021

SCIENTIFIC JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

- 1. Shvetsova Anastasia A., **Lazarenko Varvara S.**, Gaynullina Dina K., Tarasova Olga S., Schubert Rudolf (2022). TWIK-Related Acid-Sensitive Potassium Channels (TASK-1) Emerge as Contributors to Tone Regulation in Renal Arteries at Alkaline pH. *Frontiers in physiology*, *13*: 895863. https://doi.org/10.3389/fphys.2022.895863
- 2. **Lazarenko Varvara**, Shvetsova Anastasia, Gaynullina Dina, Schubert Rudolph (2020). TASK-1 Channels Play an Anticontractile Role in Rat Septal Coronary Artery Under Pharmacological Blockade of Endothelium. *Artery Research*, 26(S1): S58. https://doi.org/10.2991/artres.k.201209.048
- 3. Borzykh A.A., Kuzmin I.V., Kiryukhina O.O., Selivanova E.K., Shvetsova A.A., **Lazarenko V.S.**, Los-Arkos Uvarova S., Nesterenko A.M., Tarasova O.S. (2020). Voluntary running training of female rats during gestation: characteristics of an experimental model [in Russian]. *Aviakosmicheskaya i Ekologicheskaya Meditsina*, *54*(2): 89–95. https://www.elibrary.ru/item.asp?id=42721639

CERTIFICATES

2023	A FELASA accredited course on Laboratory Animal Science (EU function B) at Radboudumc
2021	An upgrade training on ICH guidelines on Good Clinical Practice (GCP) at LABMGMU

ACADEMIC HONORS AND AWARDS

2022-2024	Awarded Orange Tulip Scholarship for the studies at Radboud University
2020-2021	Awarded MSU Increased State Academic Scholarship for scientific and academic achievements
2021	Second prize-winner in the Lomonosov Universiade on modern problems of biology

DIGITAL SKILLS

Python (beginner), DeepLabCut, STATISTICA, GraphPad Prism, Rotor-Gene Q Series, and MS Office softwares

LANGUAGES

Russian (native), English (fluent – C_2), German (intermediate – B_1 - B_2), Dutch (low intermediate – A_2 - B_1), French (beginner - A_1)

VOLUNTEERING ACTIVITY

2024	Mentorship of the international exchange and Master's students at the Radboud Intro
2023	Organization of the BBB Career Event 2023, Nijmegen
2022-2023	Organization of volleyball tournaments in the international volleyball group at Radboud
2018-2021	Mentorship of the first-year students at Faculty of Biology, MSU, Moscow

HOBBIES

Animals (horses & dogs), volleyball, reading, drawing, guitar playing, traveling

Лазаренко Варвара Сергеевна / Lazarenko Varvara

4.3. Сведения о результатах освоения образовательной программы / Programme details and results gained

N	Наименование дисциплин (модулей) программы / Title of programme courses (modules)	Зачетные единицы / Общее количество часов (в том числе аудиторных) / Credits / Academic hours (including in-class hours)	Оценка / Mark
1	Английский язык / English language	8 / 288 (208)	отлично / excellent
2	Экономика / Economics	4 / 144 (60)	зачтено / passed
3	Философия / Philosophy	2 / 72 (24)	зачтено / passed
	История / History		
4	Отечественная история / History of Russia	2 / 72 (24)	зачтено / passed
5	История и методология биологии / History and methodology of	2 / 72 (28)	зачтено / passed
٠	biology Русский язык и культура речи / Russian language and standard of	-, -, -, -,	
	speech		
6	Русский язык / Russian language	2 / 72 (36)	зачтено / passed
7	Риторика / Rhetoric	2 / 72 (36)	зачтено / passed
		2 / 72 (72)	зачтено / passed
8	Физическая культура / Physical training	2 / 12 (12)	
9	Элективные курсы по физической культуре / Elective courses in physical training		зачтено / passed
10	Безопасность жизнедеятельности / Life safety	2 / 72 (36)	зачтено / passed
11	Биоэтика / Bioethics	4 / 144 (36)	зачтено / passed
	Современное естествознание / Modern natural sciences		
12	Геология / Geology	2 / 72 (36)	зачтено / passed
13	География / Geography	2 / 72 (36)	зачтено / passed
14	Почвоведение / Soil science	2 / 72 (24)	зачтено / passed
15	Проблемы современной биологии / Current challenges in biology	2 / 72 (36)	зачтено / passed
16	Клеточная биология / Cell biology	3 / 108 (90)	отлично / excellent
17	Охрана природы / Environment protection Математика / Mathematics	2 / 72 (24)	зачтено / passed
18	Высшая математика / Higher mathematics	6 / 216 (198)	отлично / excellent
19	Математические методы в биологии / Mathematical methods in biology	3 / 108 (72)	хорошо / good
20	Физика / Physics Химия / Chemistry	5 / 180 (150)	отлично / excellent
21	Общая и неорганическая химия / General and inorganic chemistry	4 / 144 (108)	отлично / excellent
22	Органическая химия / Organic chemistry	5 / 180 (156)	отлично / excellent
23	Аналитическая химия / Analytical chemistry	3 / 108 (72)	отлично / excellent
24	Физическая химия / Physical chemistry	3 / 108 (72)	хорошо / good
25	Коллоидная химия / Colloid chemistry	2 / 72 (24)	зачтено / passed
	Информатика / Computer science		1447000
26	Биоинформатика / Bioinformatics	3 / 108 (60)	зачтено / passed
27	Математическое моделирование в биологии / Mathematical modelling in biology	2 / 72 (54)	отлично / excellent
	Зоология / Zoology		
28	Зоология беспозвоночных / Invertebrate zoology	5 / 180 (126)	хорошо / good
29	Зоология позвоночных / Zoology of vertebrates Ботаника / Botany	4 / 144 (120)	хорошо / good
30	Микология и альгология / Mycology and phycology	4 / 144 (108)	отлично / excellent
31	Высшие растения / Higher plants	5 / 180 (120)	отлично / excellent
32	Микробиология с основами биотехнологии микроорганизмов / Microbiology and fundamentals of microbial biotechnology	5 / 180 (120)	отлично / excellent
33	Вирусология / Virology	2 / 72 (28)	отлично / excellent
34	Методы современной биологии / Modern methods in biology	2 / 72 (36)	зачтено / passed
35	Гистология / Histology	2 / 72 (60)	хорошо / good
36	Эмбриология / Embryology	3 / 108 (72)	отлично / excellent
37	Физиология человека и животных / Human and animal physiology	3 / 108 (90)	отлично / excellent
38	Физиология высшей нервной деятельности / Physiology of higher nervous activity	2 / 72 (28)	зачтено / passed

N	Наименование дисциплин (модулей) программы / Title of programme courses (modules)	Зачетные единицы / Общее количество часов (в том числе аудиторных) / Credits / Academic hours (including in-class hours)	Оценка / Mark
39	Физиология растений / Plant physiology	3 / 108 (90)	отлично / excellent
40	Основы молекулярной биологии / Foundations of molecular biology	2 / 72 (28)	отлично / excellent
41	Биофизика / Biophysics	5 / 180 (120)	хорошо / good
42	Генетика / Genetics	4 / 144 (120)	отлично / excellent
43	Иммунология / Immunology	3 / 108 (42)	хорошо / good
44	Теории эволюции / Evolution theories	3 / 108 (70)	отлично / excellent
45	Экология / Ecology	2 / 72 (36)	отлично / excellent
46	Антропология с основами анатомии / Anthropology and fundamentals of anatomy	2 / 72 (60)	зачтено / passed
47	Биохимия / Biochemistry	5 / 180 (126)	отлично / excellent
48	Практическая биология / Practical biology	8 / 288 (168)	зачтено / passed
49	Клиническая психология обыденной жизни / Clinical psychology of everyday life	1 / 36 (26)	зачтено / passed
50	Основы астрономии / The basics of astronomy	1 / 36 (30)	зачтено / passed
51	Обязательные дисциплины профиля / General obligatory courses Морфология центральной нервной системы / Morphology of central nervous system	2 / 72 (54)	отлично / excellent
52	Физиология висцеральных систем / Physiology of visceral systems and peptides	3 / 108 (96)	зачтено / passed
53	Патофизиология / Pathophysiology	2 / 72 (36)	зачтено / passed
54	Электрофизиология возбудимых клеток / Electrophysiology of exited cells	2 / 72 (56)	отлично / excellent
55	Введение в эндокринологию / Introduction to endocrinology	2 / 72 (56)	зачтено / passed
56	Физиология кровообращения / Physiology of circulation	2 / 72 (24)	отлично / excellent
57	Введение в общую физиологию / Introduction to general physiology	2 / 72 (54)	зачтено / passed
58	Частная физиология / Some chapters of physiology	2 / 72 (60)	отлично / excellent
59	Избранные разделы биохимии / Selected chapters of biochemistry	3 / 108 (84)	отлично / excellent
60	Физиология выделительной системы / Physiology of excretory system	2 / 72 (24)	отлично / excellent
61	Дисциплины профиля по выбору / Optional profile subjects Молекулярная электрофизиология сердца / Molecular electrophysiology of the heart	2 / 72 (60)	отлично / excellent
62	Практическая физиология висцеральных систем / Practical physiology of visceral systems	3 / 108 (72)	зачтено / passed
63	Практическая физиология центральной нервной системы / Practical physiology of the central nervous system	3 / 108 (84)	зачтено / passed
64	Сравнительная физиология центральной нервной системы и поведения / Comparative physiology of the central nervous system and behavior	1 / 36 (28)	зачтено / passed
65	Физиология центральной нервной системы / Physiology of central nervous system	1 / 36 (28)	зачтено / passed
66	Частная физиология дыхания / Some chapters of physiology of breathing	2 / 72 (48)	зачтено / passed
	Курсовые работы / Course papers: не предусмотрены / not required		
	Практики / Practical training:		
67	Учебная практика после 1-го курса / Summer practice after 1st year	12 / 432 (0)	отлично / excellent
68	Учебная практика после 2-го курса / Summer practice after 2nd year	12 / 432 (0)	отлично / excellent
69	Учебно-производственная практика после 3-го курса / Internship after 3rd year	12 / 432 (0)	отлично / excellent

			Trintant Control of Co
N	Наименование дисциплин (модулей) программы / Title of programme courses (modules)	Зачетные единицы / Общее количество часов (в том числе аудиторных) / Credits / Academic hours (including in-class hours)	Оценка / Магк
70	Преддипломная / Pre-graduation	6 / 216 (0)	зачтено / passed
71	Итоговые государственные экзамены / Final State Examinations: Государственный экзамен по профилю "Физиология человека и животных" / State examination in Human and Animal Physiology	3 / 108 (0)	хорошо / good
72	Выполнение и защита итоговой квалификационной работы / Accomplishment and defence of final qualifying paper: Тема: "Вклад TASK-1 каналов в регуляцию тонуса артерий разных органов у крыс" / Subject: "Role of TASK-1 channels in arterial tone regulation in different organs in rats" ИТОГО / ТОТАL	6 / 216 (0) 240 / 8640(4460)	отлично / excellent
1	Изучено студентом сверх учебного плана / Extracurricular courses: Частная физиология пищеварения / Some chapters of gastrointestinal physiology	2 / 72 (36)	зачтено / passed
2	Частная физиология сердечно-сосудистой системы / Some chapters of physiology of the cardiovascular system КОНЕЦ ТАБЛИЦЫ / END OF TABLE	4 / 144 (96)	зачтено / passed
		Turned Commencer	

N	Наименование дисциплин (модулей) программы / Title of programme courses (modules)	Зачетные единицы / Общее количество часов (в том числе аудиторных) / Credits / Academic hours (including in-class hours)	Оценка / Mark
			1 (A)
	M.P. Toucovagene / Grading sel		

4.4. Система оценок в Московском государственном университете имени М.В.Ломоносова / Grading scheme at Lomonosov Moscow State University Применяется следующая система оценок: «отлично», «хорошо», «удовлетворительно», «неудовлетворительно», а также «зачтено», «не зачтено»

The following grading scheme is adopted: "excellent" is the highest possible mark, "good" is the second passing mark,

The following grading scheme is adopted: "excellent" is the highest possible mark, "good" is the second passing mark, "satisfactory" is the lowest passing mark, "unsatisfactory" is a failure; for pass-or-fail examination "passed" or "failed" are the possible marks

4.5. Дополнительные сведения о дипломе / Overall classification of the diploma

H.B.Гусев / N.V.Gusev

М.П.Кирпичников / М.Р.Жirpichnikov

Е.Е.Баскакова / Е.Е.Вазкаком

приложение к **ДИПЛОМУ**

AAM 1706415

DIPLOMA

SUPPLEMENT

05z-0224-21w

Регистрационный номер / Registration number

оня 2020 года / 30 June 2020

Дата выдачи / Issued on

MA 3717926

документ содержит 8 страниц / document consists of 8 pages

страница / page 6

MASTER'S COURSES ATTENDED

4.3 Programme details and the individual grades obtained

The following index lists the courses of the programme the student has attended, the number of European Credits attributed to each course and the final mark the student has acquired for the course.

M Medical Biology	EC	Grade
Compulsory Track Courses:		
Molecular and Cellular Neurobiology	6.0	6.0
Molecular Therapy	6.0	7.0
Trends in Stem Cell Biology	3.0	6.0
33.0		
Philosophy Courses:		
Upgrading the Human?	3.0	8.0
(0.0 to 4 to 2014 and 0.4 to 2015 and 0.0 to 2014 and 0.0 to 0.0		
Master Portfolio:	from the state of	
Master Portfolio Biosciences	0.0	P
	Towns of the last	
Free Electives:		
Food and Brain Health	3.0	7.5
Review Article:	TLA	
Review Article	6.0	8.0
	9	
Internship:	4/50	1
Master (Medical) Biology SMI/SIS internship (Donders	33.0	8.5
Centre for Cognition, Netherlands)		WAR.
		< 171 1
Extracurricular Courses:		** I
Course on Laboratory Animal Sciences	3.0	8.5
Master's Specialisation Science, Management and Innovation	EC	Grade
Compulsory Courses SMI:		
Sustainable Innovation Management	6.0	7.0
Reaching the Sustainable Development Goals Reaching	6.0	7.5
the Sustainable Development Goa		
Methods in Societal Research: Science, Management &	3.0	8.5
Innovation		
Themes SMI:		
The Future of Health	6.0	7.5
How Health Systems Work	6.0	6.0
Advanced Endocrinology	3.0	6.0
SMI Final Research Project:		
Science, Management and Innovation Research Project	30.0	8.0
(HAN University of Applied Sciences, Netherlands)	30.0	0.0
Total EC:	123.0	
Total Eo.	120.0	

Page 5 of 9

Varvara Lazarenko

REFEREES

- Geert Frederix, supervisor of the master thesis, geert.frederix@han.nl
- Stijn Boeren, daily supervisor of the master thesis, stijn.boeren@hotmail.com
- Janneke Grutters, the second reviewer of the master thesis, janneke.grutters@radboudumc.nl